Harsh Mriduhash



harshsahay2709@gmail.com



9674783793



linkedin.com/in/harsh-s-2ab5a0158

Summary

A MERN stack developer with 5 years of experience in taking businesses from O to 1. With an excellent way of storytelling through my technical expertise. Technical expertise in HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, JAVASCRIPT, ES6, DOM MANIPULATION, REACT.js, NPM, WEBPACK, REDUX(Thunk, Saga), HOOKS, NODE.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, REDIS, TYPESCRIPT, NEXT.js, OOP, JEST, GraphQL, Restful APIs, DOCKER, KUBERNETES, AWS(EC2 S3):- Monolithic, Microservices, Lambda, SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE, SYSTEM DESIGN. Git/CI/CD, SSH, PERFORMANCE OPTIMISATION, SOCKETS, SPA, PWA, JWT, Firebase, Security.

Experience



Founding Engineer & Tech Lead

DocVita

May 2022 - Mar 2023 (11 months)

- Working directly with CTO & Build the entire Architecture of the product.
- Demonstrated ability to build and in architecting of WebApp and deploy on cloud platforms such as AWS with microservices architecture.
- Build the frontend on React.js & drove the workflows (& used supplementary libraries like Redux, & other react ecosystem) with speed optimization.
- Worked with RDBMS SQL, NoSQL databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL. Understanding of UI development like PWA, SPA. Good exposure in High & Low Level Designs. Writing clean, well-organized, maintainable, reusable code
- Ensure strong compliance with TDD, SOLID, DRY, code reviews and define success criteria for testing with JEST, mocha, jasmine, chai & product acceptance.
- Deep understanding of web technologies (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3).
- Best practices of SDLC such as Deployments, Release management, Familiarity to MVC, SOAP, REST APIs web services.
- Experience of leading & mentoring development teams, performing code reviews

cinta Frontend Lead

Cinta Medtech

Aug 2020 - Mar 2022 (1 year 8 months)

- Deciding the frontend architecture for large userbase(React, Next, Gatsby)
- Experience architecting, developing and delivering large single-page applications with hundreds of APIs with fast release cycles.
- Taken broad, conceptual ideas and smoothly turn them into congruent scenarios, usable flows, and simple, intuitive interfaces with smoothness.
- Created wireframes, storyboards, user flows and process flows to effectively communicate interaction and design ideas
- · Leading the team of developers and Performing code reviews and mentoring junior developers.
- · Maintain and improve website performance, Optimize applications for maximum speed.
- Experience of consuming REST and GraphQL APIs

Web Developer

Railofy

Sep 2019 - Aug 2020 (1 year)

- build the entire web application on MERN stack (www.railofy.com).
- Solved the major issue with regards to traveling & provided travel assurance.
- Joined as founding engineer, coordinated with backend devs & designers.
- After finalizing the design of frontend, Used React.js for making web pages.

Web Developer

Freelancer.com

Dec 2018 - Nov 2019 (1 year)

- --> Started Freelancing in Web Development through different platforms
- --> Began with only HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, REACT.
- --> Worked with 30 different clients from different parts of the world.

Web Developer

InWara Inc Jan 2018 - Dec 2018 (1 year)

Education

Techno India University

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Software Engineering 2014 - 2018

Skills

Software Architecture • JavaScript • React.js • Node.js • TypeScript • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Databases • DevOps • Next.js • Systems Design